<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This XML format is not at all official. I invented it. murrayc. 2014-07-29. -->
<!-- This was generated by murrayc_tree_exporter.coffee -->
<murrayc_zoonverse_questions xmlns="http://murrayc.com/murrayc_zoonverse_questions" format_version="1">
  <question id="decals-0">
    <title>Shape</title>
    <text>Is the galaxy simply smooth and rounded, with no sign of a disk?</text>
    <help>The aim here is to divide featureless galaxies from all the rest. If you can see any interesting features at all, click "features or disk." Just occasionally you might see something that isn't a galaxy at all — the long streak of a satellite, for example, or an image swamped by light from a bright star. If this happens, just click "star or artifact". Click on the images to see larger examples.</help>
    <answer id="a-0" icon="smooth_round" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-8">
      <text>Smooth</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-1" icon="feature_clumpy" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-1">
      <text>Features or disk</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-2" icon="star" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-11">
      <text>Star or artifact</text>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="decals-1">
    <title>Disk</title>
    <text>Could this be a disk viewed edge-on?</text>
    <help>Disc galaxies are very thin, so they look different when viewed from the side. We're trying to find exactly edge-on galaxies with this question. If the galaxy looks needle-like, perhaps with a bulge at the centre, then click "yes," otherwise choose "no" (even for galaxies that are almost edge-on). Click on the images to see larger examples.</help>
    <answer id="a-0" icon="yes" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-7">
      <text>Yes</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-1" icon="no" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-2">
      <text>No</text>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="decals-10">
    <title>Odd</title>
    <text>Do you see any of these odd features in the image?</text>
    <help>These are examples of galaxy morphology that are rare, but still important to note when you see them. You can select more than one option if you see multiple features in the same galaxy. Ring galaxies have a bright circle of stars around the edge of the galaxy. Lenses and arcs are curved, detached bands of light that can be caused by gravitational lensing. Irregular galaxies have shapes that are neither smooth ellipses or well-behaved spirals, but look more like a chaotic blob. Dust lanes are thin, dark features across a galaxy that resemble shadows. Overlapping galaxies occur when two galaxies appear to be located at least partially on top of each other, but where you don't see any distortions or features that would indicate a merger. Click to see larger images.</help>
    <answer id="a-0" icon="yes" examplesCount="0" leadsTo="decals-11">
      <text>Done</text>
    </answer>
    <checkbox id="x-0" icon="no" examplesCount="0">
      <text>None</text>
    </checkbox>
    <checkbox id="x-1" icon="ring" examplesCount="6">
      <text>Ring</text>
    </checkbox>
    <checkbox id="x-2" icon="lens" examplesCount="3">
      <text>Lens or arc</text>
    </checkbox>
    <checkbox id="x-3" icon="irregular" examplesCount="4">
      <text>Irregular</text>
    </checkbox>
    <checkbox id="x-4" icon="other" examplesCount="2">
      <text>Other</text>
    </checkbox>
    <checkbox id="x-5" icon="dustlane" examplesCount="6">
      <text>Dust lane</text>
    </checkbox>
    <checkbox id="x-6" icon="overlapping" examplesCount="6">
      <text>Overlapping</text>
    </checkbox>
  </question>
  <question id="decals-11">
    <title>Discuss</title>
    <text>Would you like to discuss this object?</text>
    <help>If you have any questions about this object, or think it may be interesting to others, or just have something to say, you can start a discussion on Talk by clicking "Yes". Talk will open in a new window - just close it to come back to the classification page.</help>
    <answer id="a-0" icon="yes" examplesCount="0">
      <text>Yes</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-1" icon="no" examplesCount="0">
      <text>No</text>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="decals-2">
    <title>Bar</title>
    <text>Is there any sign of a bar feature through the centre of the galaxy?</text>
    <help>Sometimes galaxies have a prominent straight "bar" running through their centre, and that's what we're looking for here. Click on the images to see larger examples.</help>
    <answer id="a-0" icon="yes" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-3">
      <text>Bar</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-1" icon="no" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-3">
      <text>No bar</text>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="decals-3">
    <title>Spiral</title>
    <text>Is there any sign of a spiral arm pattern?</text>
    <help>Look carefully for spiral arms — remember they may be embedded in the disk and not that easy to see. Click on the images to see larger examples.</help>
    <answer id="a-0" icon="yes" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-5">
      <text>Spiral</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-1" icon="no" examplesCount="4" leadsTo="decals-4">
      <text>No spiral</text>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="decals-4">
    <title>Bulge</title>
    <text>How prominent is the central bulge, compared with the rest of the galaxy?</text>
    <help>It's not always easy to tell, but look at the centre of the galaxy for a round bulge of stars which may obscure any bar and the spiral arms in this central region. If you see a bulge, rank its size and brightness compared to the rest of the galaxy's disk. Click on the images to see larger examples.</help>
    <answer id="a-0" icon="bulge_none" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-9">
      <text>No bulge</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-1" icon="bulge_obvious" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-9">
      <text>Obvious</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-2" icon="bulge_dominant" examplesCount="4" leadsTo="decals-9">
      <text>Dominant</text>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="decals-5">
    <title>Spiral</title>
    <text>How tightly wound do the spiral arms appear?</text>
    <help>Astronomers classify spiral galaxies by how tight their arms are — you might find it easiest to assess this by looking at the arms where they're closest to the centre. Click on the images to see larger examples.</help>
    <answer id="a-0" icon="spiral_tight" examplesCount="5" leadsTo="decals-6">
      <text>Tight</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-1" icon="spiral_medium" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-6">
      <text>Medium</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-2" icon="spiral_loose" examplesCount="4" leadsTo="decals-6">
      <text>Loose</text>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="decals-6">
    <title>Spiral</title>
    <text>How many spiral arms are there?</text>
    <help>Some spiral galaxies are rather complicated, but we want your best guess as to how many individual arms you can see. Note that the arms don't always begin at the very centre of the galaxy. If there are more than four arms, don't worry about counting them individually, but select the "more than 4" button. Click on the images to see larger examples.</help>
    <answer id="a-0" icon="spiral_1" examplesCount="4" leadsTo="decals-4">
      <text>1</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-1" icon="spiral_2" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-4">
      <text>2</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-2" icon="spiral_3" examplesCount="5" leadsTo="decals-4">
      <text>3</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-3" icon="spiral_4" examplesCount="5" leadsTo="decals-4">
      <text>4</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-4" icon="spiral_4-plus" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-4">
      <text>More than 4</text>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="decals-7">
    <title>Bulge</title>
    <text>Does the galaxy have a bulge at its centre?</text>
    <help>Concentrate on the centre of the galaxy — if it has a smooth, uninterrupted, needle or lens-shape then click "no bulge." Otherwise your options are "rounded" or "boxy" bulges (but boxy bulges are rare). Click on the images to see larger examples.</help>
    <answer id="a-0" icon="edge_round" examplesCount="4" leadsTo="decals-9">
      <text>Rounded</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-1" icon="edge_boxy" examplesCount="5" leadsTo="decals-9">
      <text>Boxy</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-2" icon="edge_none" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-9">
      <text>No bulge</text>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="decals-8">
    <title>Round</title>
    <text>How rounded is it?</text>
    <help>Not all galaxies are perfectly round - just look at the overall shape and put it in one of these three categories. If there's more than one galaxy in the field, remember always to concentrate on the one in the centre. Click on the images to see larger examples.</help>
    <answer id="a-0" icon="smooth_round" examplesCount="5" leadsTo="decals-9">
      <text>Completely round</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-1" icon="smooth_in-between" examplesCount="5" leadsTo="decals-9">
      <text>In between</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-2" icon="smooth_cigar" examplesCount="4" leadsTo="decals-9">
      <text>Cigar shaped</text>
    </answer>
  </question>
  <question id="decals-9">
    <title>Mergers</title>
    <text>Is the galaxy currently merging or is there any sign of tidal debris?</text>
    <help>Now you can look at the larger picture — if the galaxy is colliding with another, click "merger." If there's no visible second system, but long streams of stars or gas are visible then click "tidal debris." "Both" and "Neither" are your other options. Click on the images to see larger examples.</help>
    <answer id="a-0" icon="merger" examplesCount="4" leadsTo="decals-10">
      <text>Merging</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-1" icon="tidal-debris" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-10">
      <text>Tidal debris</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-2" icon="merger_tidal" examplesCount="6" leadsTo="decals-10">
      <text>Both</text>
    </answer>
    <answer id="a-3" icon="no" examplesCount="4" leadsTo="decals-10">
      <text>Neither</text>
    </answer>
  </question>
</murrayc_zoonverse_questions>
